# Harshita Chauhan

Software Engineer, 189 PR Holder

A Software Engineer at heart, a book lover by blood and a geek by nature! A curious problem solver, looking to build on my extensive range of technical skills within a suitably challenging role.



Marsh.101186@gmail.com

0480121277

Essendon North, Melbourne, Australia

in linkedin.com/in/harshitachauhan

## **ABOUT ME**

With 10+ years of Software Development experience, 6+ years of Technical Lead experience, I enjoy being an important part of a successfully growing and productive software engineering team. I am quick to grasp new ideas and concepts and deliver creative solutions for customer problems. I'm able to work well on my own initiative and demonstrate the high levels of motivation required to meet the tightest of deadlines.

Currently I am volunteering at a newly found Australian subsidiary of an Indian IT firm, Tricon Infotech. The Australian subsidiary is called Tricon Infotech Pty Ltd, head quartered in Melbourne.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Principal Member Technical Staff** Oracle India Pvt. Ltd

05/2011 - 07/2019 Database Development Bangalore, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Lead and coached a team of 3-4 people with varying skills and backgrounds working on Oracle DB releases as backend developers.
- Worked on definition, design and development of Oracle High Availability Agents(HAA) module of Oracle Real Application Cluster using C++ and Java.
- Developed and maintained the automation test framework(simulation of real life scenarios in form of long and short regressions) for HAA module of Oracle Real Application Cluster using Java, C, Perl, PL/SQL/Shell/Ora\*tst scripting.
- Worked on development and maintenance of the automation test framework for Oracle Cloud Infrastructure -Identity and Access Management.
- Worked on development and maintenance of the automation test framework for Java APIs for SRVM module(srvctl utility) of Oracle Real Application Cluster.
- Participated in technical discussion forum, Discover @ Work, and various team building activities.
- Successfully managed various Oracle 12g/18g/19g/20g DB projects like Full DB In-memory caching, RAC Diagnostics, SIHA, Oracle ReadOnly Home, Oracle Consolidated Database, Oracle Autostart.

Contact: Alan Tam - siu.tam@oracle.com

# **SKILLS**



# **EDUCATION**

### **Master of Computer Applications** Motilal Nehru National Institute Of Technology

07/2006 - 05/2009

Allahabad, India

#### Achievements

- CGPA: 9.34 on a scale of 10
- Graduated among top 5 students.
- Insomnia Programming Challenge (2008) Came in top 3 programmers in an all night programming event.

### Bachelor of Science(Physics, Mathematics and Chemistry)

Chhatrapati Shahuji Maharaj University

07/2003 - 06/2006

Kanpur, India

#### Achievements

- CGPA: 76.81 on a scale of 100
- Gold Medalist in Science Division Scored highest marks in the Science division in all three years of graduation.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Application Software Engineer** ST Microelectronics

03/2010 - 05/2011

NCR. India

Achievements/Tasks

- In a team of 5, worked on definition, design, development and maintenance of project Product Referential Information System (PRIS) using technologies Tuxedo, Pro\*C, Oracle, Java and PL/SQL for backend development and Shell/Perl scripting for test automation.
- Arranged discussions with the Manufacturing team, gathered requirements for new PRIS projects, maintained backend database, UI of the web application using OpenRoad.
- Initiated and participated in technical forum 'Tech Talk's.

Contact: Narendra Jain – narendra.jain@st.com

### Software Engineer

Ma Foi Management Consultancy(Deputized at ST Microelectronics)

06/2009 - 02/2010

NCR, India

Achievements/Tasks

 Worked with ST Microelectronics as a contractor from Ma Foi. My responsibilities were the same as mentioned above.

Contact: Narendra Jain – narendra.jain@st.com

# **INTERESTS**

Reading in bed until my arms hurt

Meditation

Travelling/Hiking

Technology

**Blood Donation Awareness Program** 

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

### Oracle Volunteer India Team Volunteer

Contribution

- Participated in 'Plantation at Nandi Hills', an Environmental Health Awareness program in Bangalore.
- Participated in a Breast Cancer Awareness Program for underprivileged women in Bangalore.

#### Disha NGO

# Part time Library Organizer

Contribution

- Helped organize and continue to maintain libraries for underprivileged children at primary schools in Bangalore.
- Volunteer at an orphanage/school for blind children to sponsor meals on Indian festivals.

## **CERTIFICATES**

SAFe Agilist (02/2019 – Present)

Scaled Agile Community

Design Thinking for Innovation (11/2018 – Present)

University of Virginia, Coursera.org

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (08/2018 - Present)

Oracle University

### **AWARDS**

Group Performance Award for Oracle 12g release (2016)

Oracle India Pvt. Ltd

Group Performance award for contribution in Oracle 12g release.

### Star Performer (2013)

Oracle India Pvt. Ltd

 Youngest member to have received 'Star Performer' award for successful stabilization of HAA framework.

#### 5S Champion (2010)

ST Microelctronics

Awarded 5S Champion for organization skills

### Insomnia Programming Challenge (2008)

Motilal Nehru National Institute of technology, Allahabad

 Came in top 3 programmers in an all night programming event held at NIT Allahabad.

### Gold Medalist in Science Division in Graduation (2006)

Chhatrapati Shahuji Maharaj University(Kanpur University)

 Scored highest marks in the Science division in Kanpur University in all three years of graduation.

# **INTERNSHIP/PROJECTS**

Software Quality Tools – Performance Testing using HP Load Runner and Process Automation using IBM Clear Case (01/2009 – 05/2009)

- During the last semester of Masters, I worked with ST Microelectronics as an Intern for 5 months.
- Worked on HP Load Runner(performance testing) and Clear Case(version control system).
- Feasibility Analysis for OpenSTA, opensource tool for performance testing to be worked in association with Load Runner in case of more CPUs than licensed.

## **ORGANIZATIONS**

Ora\*tors Toastmaster Club

Oracle Volunteer India Team

Mentor/Project Organizer/Volunteer

Bangalore Mountaineering Club

Hiking Instructor/Guide

Vipassana Meditation(Dhamma.org)

Old Student/Helper

Bangalore Book Club